Your sister often warned me
Твоя сестра часто напоминала мне
Since we are of the royal family
раз уж мы члены императорской семьи
Supported by the people
и живём за счёт народа
We should
должны
Strive to restore Xuan
бороться за возрождение страны
Strive for the northern people
за старых жителей Севера
Body not among men
Хоть она и не мужчина
But heart fiercer than men
но её сердце куда отважнее мужского
When I recover the north
Когда я отвоюю Север
She won't just be my empress
она станет не только моей императрицей
But a hero of all Xuan
но и героем всего Сюаня
Brother-in-law
Шурин
I also wish to be like my sister
я тоже как и моя сестра
To establish the heart of heaven and earth
хочу установить порядок во Вселенной
To establish the destiny of the people
дать опору народу
To open peace
принести покой в смутные времена
Please grant this, brother-in-law
Прошу вас дайте мне шанс
Good
Хорошо
Since that's the case
Раз так
There's just one matter
есть одно дело
That only you can do
которое можешь сделать только ты
This is what Sheng'er wrote
Это написал Шэнэрь
Although there are still many areas needing improvement
Там ещё многое надо доработать
But I think
но я думаю
You can help him perfect it
ты сможешь помочь
You're his uncle
Ты его дядя
This matter
В этом деле
I only trust you
я доверяю только тебе
I hope
Я хочу
You'll go to Qingzhou
чтобы ты поехал в Цинчжоу
To organize reforms
и провёл реформу
Change the original land tax system
изменить систему налогов
From taxing by headcount
с подушного
To taxing by land
на земельный
In this way
Так
Those with more land
у кого больше земли
Will pay more tax
платит больше
Those with less land can pay less tax
у кого меньше платит меньше
If successful
Если всё пройдёт хорошо
Then extend to the whole country
распространим на всю страну
Qingzhou
Цинчжоу
That is
ведь это
Lady Chen's hometown
родной край госпожи Чэнь
What?
Чтото не так
Brother-in-law, don't worry
Не волнуйся шурин
This matter
это дело
I will definitely do well
я обязательно выполню
I said
Я же сказал
Only talk about family matters
только о семейном
Drink
Давай выпьем
Come
За